（吉野悠姫(よしのゆうき)）ああ～っ！
（生徒たち）やった～！
卒業生たちの料理で組んだ
フルコースを味わっていただく
（堂島銀(どうじまぎん)）では この合宿の
最後のプログラムを始めよう
Now then,
let us begin the final program of this camp.
You will be enjoying a full course meal prepared by the alumni.
All right!
The Man They Called the Demon
All students, please gather your belongings
（アナウンス）
学生は荷物をまとめ―
and prepare to board your designated bus.
それぞれ指定されたバスに
乗車してください
Please return your room keys to the front desk.
部屋の鍵はフロントへ返却
各自―
Please check your surroundings to avoid leaving anything behind.
忘れ物のないように
気をつけましょう
Oh, man!
（悠姫）いやあ～！
We're done. We're finally done!
（悠姫）終わった 終わった～
（榊涼子(さかきりょうこ)）フフ…
Everyone in Polar Star made it.
（伊武崎峻(いぶさきしゅん)）
無事に全員 生き残ったな
Yup.
（佐藤昭二(さとうしょうじ)）なあ
（青木大吾(あおきだいご)）なっ
Yeah.
It all passed by in a flash.
（田所恵(たどころめぐみ)）何だか
あっという間な気がするよ
It was pretty challenging, though!
ほんと
（涼子）大変だったけどね
No kidding!
（悠姫）ほんまやで
You didn't all need to barge into
my room on the last night!
（丸井善二(まるいぜんじ)）最後の夜まで―
僕の部屋に
集まらなくてもいいじゃないか
Didn't you enjoy yourself
the last time we came over?
丸井も盛り上がってたじゃねえか
（丸井）ドキッ
Yeah, last night too.
昨日の夜だって…
C'mon, draw the old maid!
さあ 引け　ババを引け
Let's finish the game back at the dorm!
（青木･佐藤）寮で続きやろうぜ
What?!
（丸井）なっ…
（佐藤）一色先輩も誘うか？
Maybe Isshiki-senpai can join in.
We can play Presidents and Assholes too.
（青木）“大貧民”でもいいぞ
（幸平創真(ゆきひらそうま)）あっ？
Shinomiya-senpai!
（創真）四宮先輩
（四宮小次郎(しのみやこじろう)）フッ…
So the two of you survived.
（四宮）
お前ら２人とも生き残ったな
Yeah, we managed to get by somehow.
いやあ 何とか おかげさまで
A suitcase?
その荷物…
もうフランスに戻るんですか？
Are you going back to France already?
Yes.
ああ　いつまでも
店を閉めてるわけにはいかねえ
I can't keep my restaurant closed for too long.
Besides, I've decided what my goal is going to be.
それに当面の目標が決まったからな
I'm going to make SHINO'S the number one
three-star restaurant in all of Paris.
俺の店“SHINO'S(シノズ)”を
パリで一番の名店にして―
三つ星を取りに行く
There's so much more I want to do.
他にもまだまだ
やりたいことがある
Getting the Pluspol award was just the beginning.
プルスポール勲章だけじゃ―
物足りなくなってきたところだ
A three salt plum restaurant?
“三つ干(ぼ)し”？
Wow!
すごい
No Japanese chef in France has ever received three Michelin stars!
三つ星ってフランスにいる
日本人シェフはまだ誰も―
取ったことないのに
I don't suppose—
お前ら…
Stop right there!
（乾日向子(いぬいひなこ)）待て～い！
You're not going to steal a march
on us, Shinomiya-senpai!
抜け駆けなんてさせませんよ
四宮先輩
I have no idea what you're talking about.
何のことだか分からねえな
Yukihira Souma,
（水原冬美(みずはらふゆみ)）幸平創真
イタリア料理に興味はない？
are you interested in Italian cuisine, by any chance?
Huh?
Tadokoro-kun, your talent would flourish at a sushi restaurant—
（関守平(せきもりひとし)）田所君
君の才能は鮨店でこそ伸び…
No way!
（乾）いいえ！
（恵）あっ？
To ensure Megumi-chan's safety, I'd better take her with me!
恵ちゃんは私が大切に
お持ち帰りします
Uh, what?!
は… はい～？
（堂島銀(どうじまぎん)）ハハ…
もう声をかけてるのか
I see you two have already been approached.
（乾）ウフフ～
（恵）堂島シェフ こ… これは？
Ch-Chef Doujima, wh-what's going on?
The chefs have been sizing you up.
“品定め”というやつだ
Sizing Up
Sizing us up?
品定め？
This camp also serves as an opportunity for chefs to offer students a position after graduation.
この合宿は学園を卒業した後の―
Recruit
リクルートの材料にもなると
いうことだ
In order to come here, alumni temporarily close their restaurants,
（瀬名(せな)博巳(ひろみ)）卒業生たちは
自分の店を休みにしたり―
or even let their sous chefs take over for them.
副料理長に任せてまでして
ここに来てくれている
It's partly so they can recruit future staff.
それは人材確保の場でも
あるからなんだ
Finding promising chefs is a challenging task.
（瀬名）資質ある料理人を探すのは
簡単なことではないからね
Huh, okay.
ああ なるほど
I had no idea there was another purpose to the training camp.
この合宿に
そんな意味があったなんて…
Megumi probably doesn't realize
what it means to get recruited by that lot.
恵 あのメンバーに誘われた意味
分かってなさそうね
Uh-huh.
（５人）うん うん
Yukihira-kun, you would shine
here at Tohtsuki Resort.
幸平君 君なら遠月(とおつき)リゾートでも
物になるだろう
You're welcome to join us.
いつでも歓迎するよ
I appreciate the offer,
ありがたい話っすけど―
but I already have Yukihira.
俺には“ゆきひら”があるんで
Yukihira
That's right,
（堂島）そうか
Yukihira
your family ran a restaurant, didn't it?
君の実家も料理店だったな
Yes, my father and I kept the
place running by ourselves.
はい
親父と２人で
切り盛りしてきた店です
I don't know where he is or what he's doing,
今はどこで何してんだか
分かんないけど―
but I want him to recognize my skills one day...
いつか絶対
あの親父に認められて―
and to deem me worthy of taking over Yukihira.
“ゆきひら”を背負う―
料理人になりたいんす
Senpai, you're really going to try for those stars?
先輩 三つ星 狙うんですって？
You heard?
聞こえてたのかよ
How about I come and help you out?
何なら私がお手伝いに
行ってあげましょうか？
Sure, I was thinking that I could use a servant.
そうだな
召使としてなら雇ってやるよ
Are you kidding me?!
（乾）何ですと～？
Doujima-san?
（瀬名）堂島さん
Is something wrong?
どうかなさいましたか？
No, it's nothing.
ああ… いや
Okay, Souma-kun, this is our bus.
（恵）それじゃあ 創真君
私たち こっちだから
All right, see you later.
（創真）ああ また後でな
Crap, my headband!
やべっ 手ぬぐい
（創真）くっ…
（新戸緋沙子(あらとひさこ)）えっ？
Huh, you left something behind?
（緋沙子）忘れ物ですか？
It's almost departure time.
まもなく出発です
Let me go—
（緋沙子）私が取りに行き…
（薙切(なきり)えりな）いいの
I-It's all right!
I can go get it myself!
自分で行きます
I'll go back in a different vehicle,
私は別の車で
学園へ戻りますから―
so you should go on ahead.
Take my luggage with you.
あなたは先に帰って
私の荷物を運んでおいて
O-Okay!
（緋沙子）あっ あ… はい
Whew.
It's a good thing I found it!
見つかってよかった
Well, that was a thoroughly enjoyable resort, wasn't it?
（老人Ａ）いやあ 堪能したのう
遠月リゾート
Shoot, wrong bus.
（創真）ま… 間違えた
I'm already looking forward to next year's camp!
（老人Ｂ）
来年も楽しみじゃな
Note: When there is a
cluster of express buses,
it is easy to mistake
which one is yours.
When there is a cluster of tour buses,
（アナウンス）
高速バスなどが
密集すると―
it is easy to mistake another bus for yours.
非常に
間違いやすくなります
We strongly suggest
that you confirm the
parking spot and
bus number if you
have to step outside.
We strongly suggest that you confirm the parking spot
Souma's Current Location
バスを離れる時は
必ず駐車位置や―
Souma's Current Location
ナンバーを
覚えておきましょう
and bus number if you need to step outside.
Souma's Current Location
（鶏卵(けいらん)の徳蔵(とくぞう)）おう
Oh, you're the boy who made the souffle omelette.
Souma's Current Location
Tokuzou of the Chicken Egg
お前さん スフレ･
オムレツの子じゃな
Hey, the chicken egg guy.
あっ 鶏卵の…
That wasn't bad at all.
（徳蔵）ありゃあ
なかなかの出来だったよ
Um...
（創真）あの…
I'm sorry I wasted so many of your eggs!
卵いくつもダメにして
すいませんでした
Hm, I guess you did do that.
う～ん そうじゃな
But I'll forgive you if you'll give my eggs preference
だが徳蔵印の卵を
ひいきにしてくれるなら構わんよ
in your own restaurant someday. Okay?
いつかお前さんの持つ店で… な？
I sure will!
うっす
Kousuke of the String Bean
I hope you'll use my beans too, boy!
（さやいんげんの耕助(こうすけ)）
うちのさやいんげんも
頼むぞ 君
My cheese too.
Kyuusaku of the Natural Cheese
（ナチュラルチーズの久作(きゅうさく)）
うちのチーズもな
Hey, would you like some rice crackers?
（老婦人Ａ）坊や
せんべい食べるかい？
Take these cough drops.
（老婦人Ｂ）
のどあめ 持っていきなさい
Oh, thanks.
（創真）ああ どうもっす
ああ どうも
Thanks! Thank you!
アハ… ありがとうございます
Wait, I need to get going!
…って
こんなことしてる場合じゃねえ！
Where's my bus?
（創真）えっ 俺のバス…
Um...
えっと…
Uh...
I got left behind!
（創真）置いてかれた
Seriously?
マジかよ
合宿が終わったってのに何だよ
I made it through training camp,
only to have a major crisis now?
この大ピンチは…
Wh-Why are you still here?!
なっ… 何で君がここに？
Why?
“何で？”って…
Well, it's a long story.
まあ いろいろあってな
Lady Erina!
（スタッフ）えりなお嬢様！
We've made arrangements
for a car to take you home.
車の手配できました
There happened to be one available.
ちょうど１台だけ出せる車が…
あっ？
Did he miss his bus as well?
（スタッフ）
そちらも乗り遅れた学生さんで？
Want some rice crackers?
せんべい食う？
No thank you.
食べません
Cough drops?
（創真）のどあめは？
（えりな）要りません
No need.
By the way,
（創真）そういや お前―
I remember you saying that you'd enjoy seeing me get expelled.
俺が何日目で落ちるか楽しむとか
言ってたよな？
I survived, though.
生き残ったけど何か感想ある？
So how about them apples?
（えりな）うっ… 見なくても
ドヤ顔が―
I don't even have to look to know he has a smug grin on his face.
（えりな）目に浮かぶ
（創真）へらへらへらへらへら…
（えりな）フン
You'd do well to flounder
at the very bottom of the barrel.
君はそうやってギリギリの底辺で
あがいていればいいわ
I doubt you'll get through the Selection.
どうせ選抜メンバーにも
選ばれやしないでしょうしね
The Selection?
選抜？
You don't know about it?
それも知らないの？
The Autumn Selection is a long-held Tohtsuki tradition.
遠月伝統―
Autumn Selection
“秋の選抜”よ
It's a gourmet festival where select first-years are allowed to display their skills and compete.
Autumn Selection
選び抜かれた１年生が腕を振るい
競い合う美食の祭典
Autumn Selection
The academy's board of directors and investors,
学園理事や出資者―
all heavyweights of the food industry, will be present.
一堂に会した
食の重鎮たちの前で―
It'll be the first opportunity for students to demonstrate their skills to those outside of the academy.
生徒にとっては己の力を
学外に示す最初の舞台となる
The selection process has already begun.
その選考はもう始まっているの
Didn't you notice that Selection Committee members were at the camp?
気付かなかったかしら？
合宿に―
選考委員が出入りしていたのを
Oh, so that's who they were.
（創真）ああ いた いた
It was those suits, right?
あのスーツ着た人たちか
In other words, this camp isn't just for weeding out the weak.
つまりこの合宿は
ふるい落としだけが目的ではない
It's also meant to discreetly identify
those who will ascend above the rest.
のし上がる者を見極める意図が
隠されていたのよ
A gourmet festival, huh.
美食の祭典ねえ…
Sounds like fun!
面白そうじゃん
何かこう沸き立つものがあるな
I can't help but get revved up
just thinking about it!
Like I said, there's no way someone
like you would be selected!
だから君なんかが選ばれるわけ
ないって言ってるでしょう！
What was all that about earlier, anyway?
大体 何よ　あの言いぐさ
I did learn something from my mistake.
失敗したっていう経験を得た
Learn from your mistake?
“失敗”という経験ですって？
That's what a loser says to cover up his failure.
そんなもの
負け惜しみに過ぎないわ
Failure is not an option for chefs!
料理人に失敗なんて
許されないんだから
Is that so?
（創真）そうかなあ…
（えりな）そうよ
It is!
Only perfection can be served at the table.
（えりな）テーブルには
常に完璧な品だけが求められる
That is the only way you can achieve the ultimate gourmet experience.
究極の美食というものは―
そうやってなされるの
フンッ
あの人の料理のように…
Just like his cooking.
Huh?
あっ？　何だって？
What was that?
Nothing.
何でもないわ
By the way, why'd you end up missing the bus?
そういや 薙切は
何でバスに乗り遅れたわけ？
There's no need for me to tell you.
（えりな）
君に話す必要はありません
Oh, okay.
（創真）あっそ
あ～あ
I guess this is what you'd call an awkward situation.
（創真）これはあれだな
気まずいってやつだ
Guess I'll go to sleep.
寝るか
スヤ スヤ スヤ スヤ スヤ…
Found it!
あった！
Thank goodness.
よかった…
ウフ…
I see.
（堂島）そうか
So Yukihira Souma is your son, Jouichirou.
幸平創真は―
お前の息子か
First Seat
Doujima Gin
Second Seat
Saiba Jouichirou
First Seat
Doujima Gin
Second Seat
Saiba Jouichirou
First Seat
Doujima Gin
Second Seat
Saiba Jouichirou
First Seat
Doujima Gin
Second Seat
Saiba Jouichirou
First Seat
Doujima Gin
Second Seat
Saiba Jouichirou
First Seat
Doujima Gin
Second Seat
Saiba Jouichirou
First Seat
Doujima Gin
Second Seat
Saiba Jouichirou
First Seat
Doujima Gin
Second Seat
Saiba Jouichirou
First Seat
Doujima Gin
Second Seat
Saiba Jouichirou
First Seat
Doujima Gin
Second Seat
Saiba Jouichirou
First Seat
Doujima Gin
Second Seat
Saiba Jouichirou
First Seat
Doujima Gin
Second Seat
Saiba Jouichirou
First Seat
Doujima Gin
Second Seat
Saiba Jouichirou
First Seat
Doujima Gin
Second Seat
Saiba Jouichirou
First Seat
Doujima Gin
Second Seat
Saiba Jouichirou
First Seat
Doujima Gin
Second Seat
Saiba Jouichirou
First Seat
Doujima Gin
Second Seat
Saiba Jouichirou
First Seat
Doujima Gin
Second Seat
Saiba Jouichirou
First Seat
Doujima Gin
Second Seat
Saiba Jouichirou
城一郎…
First Seat
Doujima Gin
Second Seat
Saiba Jouichirou
First Seat
Doujima Gin
Second Seat
Saiba Jouichirou
First Seat
Doujima Gin
Second Seat
Saiba Jouichirou
First Seat
Doujima Gin
Second Seat
Saiba Jouichirou
First Seat
Doujima Gin
Second Seat
Saiba Jouichirou
First Seat
Doujima Gin
Second Seat
Saiba Jouichirou
First Seat
Doujima Gin
Second Seat
Saiba Jouichirou
First Seat
Doujima Gin
Second Seat
Saiba Jouichirou
First Seat
Doujima Gin
Second Seat
Saiba Jouichirou
First Seat
Doujima Gin
Second Seat
Saiba Jouichirou
First Seat
Doujima Gin
Second Seat
Saiba Jouichirou
First Seat
Doujima Gin
Second Seat
Saiba Jouichirou
First Seat
Doujima Gin
Second Seat
Saiba Jouichirou
First Seat
Doujima Gin
Second Seat
Saiba Jouichirou
First Seat
Doujima Gin
Second Seat
Saiba Jouichirou
First Seat
Doujima Gin
Second Seat
Saiba Jouichirou
First Seat
Doujima Gin
Second Seat
Saiba Jouichirou
First Seat
Doujima Gin
Second Seat
Saiba Jouichirou
First Seat
Doujima Gin
Second Seat
Saiba Jouichirou
First Seat
Doujima Gin
Second Seat
Saiba Jouichirou
First Seat
Doujima Gin
Second Seat
Saiba Jouichirou
First Seat
Doujima Gin
Second Seat
Saiba Jouichirou
First Seat
Doujima Gin
Second Seat
Saiba Jouichirou
First Seat
Doujima Gin
Second Seat
Saiba Jouichirou
First Seat
Doujima Gin
Second Seat
Saiba Jouichirou
First Seat
Doujima Gin
Second Seat
Saiba Jouichirou
First Seat
Doujima Gin
Second Seat
Saiba Jouichirou
First Seat
Doujima Gin
Second Seat
Saiba Jouichirou
First Seat
Doujima Gin
Second Seat
Saiba Jouichirou
First Seat
Doujima Gin
Second Seat
Saiba Jouichirou
First Seat
Doujima Gin
Second Seat
Saiba Jouichirou
First Seat
Doujima Gin
Second Seat
Saiba Jouichirou
First Seat
Doujima Gin
Second Seat
Saiba Jouichirou
First Seat
Doujima Gin
Second Seat
Saiba Jouichirou
First Seat
Doujima Gin
Second Seat
Saiba Jouichirou
First Seat
Doujima Gin
Second Seat
Saiba Jouichirou
First Seat
Doujima Gin
Second Seat
Saiba Jouichirou
First Seat
Doujima Gin
Second Seat
Saiba Jouichirou
First Seat
Doujima Gin
Second Seat
Saiba Jouichirou
First Seat
Doujima Gin
Second Seat
Saiba Jouichirou
First Seat
Doujima Gin
Second Seat
Saiba Jouichirou
First Seat
Doujima Gin
Second Seat
Saiba Jouichirou
First Seat
Doujima Gin
Second Seat
Saiba Jouichirou
First Seat
Doujima Gin
Second Seat
Saiba Jouichirou
First Seat
Doujima Gin
Second Seat
Saiba Jouichirou
First Seat
Doujima Gin
Second Seat
Saiba Jouichirou
First Seat
Doujima Gin
Second Seat
Saiba Jouichirou
First Seat
Doujima Gin
Second Seat
Saiba Jouichirou
First Seat
Doujima Gin
Second Seat
Saiba Jouichirou
First Seat
Doujima Gin
Second Seat
Saiba Jouichirou
First Seat
Doujima Gin
Second Seat
Saiba Jouichirou
First Seat
Doujima Gin
Second Seat
Saiba Jouichirou
（大御堂(だいみどう)ふみ緒(お)）
ズンズ～ン ズンズ～ン
モシャ～ モシャ～
はあ ようやく合宿も終わりかい
Camp's finally over.
It's going to get noisy around here again.
また騒がしくなるねえ
That was awfully quick.
何だい　随分 早かったねえ…
ああ… やれやれまったく
Well, my goodness.
If you were coming back,
you should've called ahead!
帰ってくるなら電話の１本でも
入れたらどうなんだい？
You're still every bit as rude as you were.
相変わらず常識のない子だよ
I just happened to be passing through the area.
（幸平城一郎(ゆきひらじょういちろう)）いやあ
近くまで来たもんでね
I'm back.
ただいま
Bro, you're so funny.
Where are you, Yukihira?
Where? Where?
C'mon, where are you?
Where are you, Yukihira?
Where? Where?
C'mon, where are you?
A
Scene
from
Camp
I'm back!
（創真）ただいま～っす
We're back!
（青木）ただいま！
（一色慧(いっしきさとし)）ハハハ…
Souma-kun, I hear you came back
in one of the hotel's cars?
それじゃあ創真君はホテルの車で
帰ってきたってわけだね
I'm so jealous!
（悠姫）いいなあ
ＶＩＰじゃん ＶＩＰ
That makes you a VIP! A VIP!
It wasn't anything that fancy.
（創真）そんないいもんじゃねえよ
In any event, I'm glad everyone came back safely.
何はともあれ―
みんな無事に帰ってきてくれて
うれしいよ
You must all be tired.
みんな疲れただろう？
I'll give you guys a good meal tonight.
今夜は たっぷり
うまいもん食わせてやるよ
（佐藤）よっしゃ～！
（青木）うほっほほ～！
（悠姫）やった～！
（佐藤･青木）エッヘヘ！
Yay!
やった！
久々のふみ緒さんの料理！
We haven't had Fumio-san's cooking in forever!
Well, I won't be the one cooking.
ま 作るのはあたしじゃないがね
Hey, Souma.
（城一郎）おう 創真 帰ってきたか
手伝ってくれ
You're back.
Help me out with this.
Sure.
（創真）おう
I'd like you to prep this.
こっちの下ごしらえ頼むわ
I've already made the stock.
もう だしは―
引いてあるからよ
Sure, got it.
うん 分かった
Wait, I reacted like we're back home out of habit,
…って思わず実家のノリで
反応しちまったけど―
何やってんだ こんな所で？
but what the hell are you doing here?!
What, you know each other?
何だい 知り合いかい？
Wh-Who is he?
ど… どなたですか？
He's an alumnus of Tohtsuki Academy and a former resident of Polar Star Dormitory.
遠月学園及び極星(きょくせい)寮のＯＢだよ
A Tohtsuki alumnus?!
（創真）遠月ＯＢ？
Must be the generation gap.
ジェネレーションギャップだねえ
You don't know the former
second seat of the Elite Ten,
かつての十傑(じゅっけつ) 第二席
才波(さいば)城一郎を知らないとは
Saiba Jouichirou?
Former Second Seat of the Elite Ten
The former second seat of the Elite Ten?!
（涼子･恵･佐藤･悠姫･青木･丸井）
元十傑 第二席？
Former Second Seat of the Elite Ten
"Saiba"?
才波？
Former Second Seat of the Elite Ten
Hey, the rice is almost done, Souma.
ああ そろそろ米が炊けるぞ 創真
Forget the rice!
…って うるせえ
いいから説明しやがれ 親父！
Just tell me what's going on, Dad!
You're family?!
Son of the Former Second Seat of the Elite Ten
（８人）親子？
Hm, I see now.
う～ん なるほど
So Dad's an alumnus of Tohtsuki,
（創真）親父が遠月ＯＢで―
lived at Polar Star Dormitory,
極星寮出身で―
and was in the Elite Ten.
しかも十傑
Even for me, it's hard to take this all in.
さすがにこれを
一度にのみ込むのは気力が…
Whoa, I've never seen Souma flustered before.
（悠姫）お～っ
珍しく幸平が動揺してる
I guess it's not that unusual.
He's Yukihira-kun's father, after all.
（涼子）さすが幸平君のお父さん…
といったところかしら
So you are Jouichirou Saiba.
あなたが
ジョウイチロウ･サイバでしたか
Oh, you've heard of me?
へえ 俺を知ってるのか？
Yes, I've come across your name in past documents.
はい 過去の資料でお名前を
拝見したことがあったもので
You were described as a nomadic chef who worked his magic in famous restaurants around the world.
“世界中のあらゆる名店で
腕を振るった流浪の料理人”
But after a time,
“だがある時 料理界の第一線から
こつぜんと姿を消した―”
you vanished from the front lines.
You became a legend known only to a select few.
“知る人ぞ知る
伝説の人物である”と
I am the current seventh seat of the Elite Ten,
現十傑 第七席
一色慧と申します
Isshiki Satoshi.
I'm honored to meet you, Chef Saiba.
お会いできて光栄です
才波シェフ
Oh, I go by Yukihira now.
今は“幸平”の名前で
やってるからさ―
You can just call me Jouichirou.
“城一郎”で構わないぜ
H-He's not disturbed by Isshiki-senpai's appearance in the least.
い… 一色先輩の
格好を見ても動じない
He's not a former Elite Ten for nothing.
さすが元十傑
What's that have to do with anything?
そういう問題か
I didn't know Dad was so famous.
親父がそんなに有名だったとは…
You really had no idea?!
あんた全然知らなかったわけ？
Well, I only learned recently that he'd worked overseas before.
あ いやあ…
海外で仕事してたってことも
最近知ってさぁ
We used to get calls in languages
I didn't understand,
（創真）
なぜか時々 知らない言葉で
電話がかかってきたり―
and I'd come across tons of
photos of him with foreigners.
外国人と写ってる親父の写真が
大量に出てきたことはあったな
I thought that every family
experienced those sorts of things.
どこの家庭でも
よくあることかと思ってたんだが…
They don't!
ねえよ　気付けよ
You should've noticed!
Who knew Souma-kun's father
was such a great man?
（恵）創真君のお父さんが―
そんなにすごい人だったなんて
（城一郎）さあ
Well, let's have a toast!
乾杯といこうぜ
This is to celebrate all of you surviving the camp.
全員 合宿で生き残ったお祝いだ
Don't hold back tonight!
今日は盛大に飲み食いするよ
Thanks for the food!
（寮生たち）いただきま～す！
Cheers!
（寮生たち）乾杯！
F-Food made by a former Elite Ten member...
も… 元十傑の作った品
I wonder what it tastes like.
一体どんな味が？
Somehow... I'm really nervous.
（恵）な… 何だか緊張するよ
（恵）あっ？
（城一郎）どうぞ
Please, try some.
（皿を置く音）
召し上がれ
O-Okay!
はっ… はい
あむっ
I can see it!
（悠姫）見える
（涼子）見える
Places I've never been...
（悠姫）行ったこともない…
Vistas of foreign lands...
（涼子）異国の情景が…
It's all coming to life in my mind!
（恵）浮かんでくる
This is the essence of Arabia!
（３人）この味 まさに
アラビア～ン！
It's delicious!
（佐藤･青木）
めちゃくちゃ うまいっす！
What's this paste spread on the lamb?
ラム肉に塗ってある
このペースト―
何だろう？
That's harissa.
（城一郎）それはハリッサ
It's an all-purpose chili pepper spice blend from North Africa.
トウガラシなどから作る
北アフリカ発祥の万能調味料だ
Using traditional Middle Eastern cooking as a base,
中東の伝統料理を下敷きに―
I tried adding parsley and
garam masala this time around.
今回はパセリとガラムマサラを
混ぜてみた
J-Jouichirou-san, what's this?
じょ… 城一郎さん
これは何ですか？
That's zuppa di pesce.
（城一郎）そいつは
〝ズッパ･ディ･
ペッシェ〞
It's a Ligurian seafood soup with stocca fisso.
リグーリア風の
魚介スープに―
〝ストッカフィッソ〞を
使ってる
What about this one, Jouichirou-san?!
城一郎さん こっちは？
P-Please tell us about this too!
こ… これも教えてください
Oh, that's...
（城一郎）ああ それは…
Jouichirou-san's such a hunk.
城一郎さん 何だか
“男の人”って感じがするよ～
Yeah, he gives off this manly aura.
ええ 大人の色気ムンムンね
何だか男子まで
ときめいてない？
Even the guys are all over him.
Will Yukihira...
幸平も将来…
...turn out that way too?
（３人）ああなるのかな～？
Huh? What now?
（創真）あっ 何だよ？
They were all wound up tight
when they first met him,
（一色）
どこか委縮していた彼らが―
but a single bite has opened their hearts.
食べた途端に心を開いた
This dish is bursting with its creator's personality!
あふれてくる…
この料理を作った男の人柄が！
Whoa! This dish is awesome too!
（青木）うっほ！
これも たまんねえ
すげえ！　どれも超うめえぜ
Wow! They're all super delicious!
What about this one?
こっちはどうかな？
（城一郎）ふふん！
パクッ モグモグ…
Disgusting!
うっ まずい！
Oh, that one!
（城一郎）おお それな
先月 食った蛇料理を再現してみた
I tried to recreate a snake dish I had last month.
It's so disgusting!
（丸井）くう… くっ… くう…
（城一郎）これが まずいんだ
They chop the snake up with the skin still on,
皮付きのまま ぶつ切りにして
何の処理もせず ゆでるだけでな
and then they boil the pieces
without any further prep work.
Dad, this sucks big time!
親父 これ やべえな
Right?
だろ？
It's easily in the top ten best disgusting dishes.
過去のベスト10に入るまずさだな
Yukihira Family
Isolation Ward
Wouldn't that make it the ten worst dishes, then?
Are you sure it's not in the top four?
（伊武崎）まずいなら
ワースト10じゃないか？
Heck, maybe the top two.
Oh, I get it now.
（悠姫）そうだった…
This is Yukihira's father we're talking about.
I think the top two were those, y'know...
あくまで
幸平の親父さんだった
Well, the one quirk aside... Jouichirou.
（ふみ緒）ま ゲテモノ料理は
置いておくとして―
城一郎
They used to called you "The Demon."
かつて“修羅”と呼ばれた男が…
（創真）ん？
（ふみ緒）まあ―
But you're cooking really gentle dishes these days.
随分と優しい料理を
作るようになったねえ
Yeah.
You ought to let Gin try
a dish of yours sometime.
（ふみ緒）銀にもいつか―
食わせてやりな
I guess you're right.
（城一郎）そうだな
Gin
銀？
Gin?
Gin
You don't mean—
銀ってまさか…
Gin
That's right.
ああ
合宿で偉そうな顔してただろ？
He was acting all high and
mighty at camp, wasn't he?
Doujima Gin, the head chef of Tohtsuki Resort.
遠月リゾート総料理長
堂島銀だよ
Doujima Gin
Tohtsuki Resort
Head Chef and Company Director
Doujima Gin
High School, 2nd Year
Here, this is Gin,
（ふみ緒）
ほれ これが銀―
Saiba Jouichirou
High School, 2nd Year
and this is Jouichirou.
こっちが城一郎
They were second-year high schoolers at the time.
２人が高２の頃さ
They're both so young!
２人とも若～い
Fumio-san, please don't show them things like that.
ふみ緒さん あんまり
そういうの見せないでくれよ
Why not?
いいじゃないか
So Chef Doujima was also from Polar Star.
堂島シェフも極星寮出身だったんだ
Seriously?
マジかよ
Doujima Gin, the first seat of the Elite Ten.
十傑 第一席 堂島銀
第二席 才波城一郎
Saiba Jouichirou, the second seat.
When these two became the core,
この２人が中心になったあの頃―
Polar Star entered a golden age.
極星はまさに黄金期を迎えたのさ
We won victory after victory in Cooking Battles,
食戟(しょくげき)で連戦連勝を続け―
seized acre after acre and expanded the dorm,
土地を奪っては
寮の敷地を増やし―
Polar Star Dormitory
Annex Planned Construction Site
This is Polar Star Dormitory Property
invested in ever larger kitchen facilities,
厨房(ちゅうぼう)設備への投資―
and secured procurement routes for ingredients.
食材調達ルートの確保―
We were fully self-sufficient.
何から何まで自力で
賄(まかな)ってたからねぇ
More like, we were a nation unto ourselves!
（城一郎）もはや
独立国家みたいなもんだったよなぁ
Those fields you're using out back,
（ふみ緒）
あんたらの耕してるあの畑も―
the fermentation workshop,
麹(こうじ)用の作業場―
and the large hen house—
鶏小屋の敷地も―
all of those were built back when
Gin and Jouichirou's crew were around.
みんなあの頃 銀と城一郎たちが
手に入れたものさ
Still, while Gin never fails to send a New Year's greeting card and mid-year gift...
（ふみ緒）…にしても―
銀は毎年 年賀状と
お中元を欠かさないのに―
Jouichirou!
城一郎
Why don't you ever write a letter once in a while?
あんた たまには手紙の１つでも
寄こしたらどうだい？
I do come by to see you sometimes, don't I?
だから時々
こうやって顔見せに来てるだろ？
As if!
（ふみ緒）よく言うよ
Stray Cat
Loyal Dog
You just wander in and wander out!
ふらっとやって来ちゃ
いつも勝手に出ていって…
（悠姫･涼子）ウッフフフ…
Talk about the legendary graduate.
まさに伝説の卒業生ですね
Strictly speaking, I never actually graduated.
ま 俺は卒業してねえんだけどな
What? You didn't?
えっ そうなんですか？
But you were the second seat.
第二席なのに？
A lot of things happened.
いろいろあってな
Is Gin doing well?
（城一郎）銀は元気そうだったか？
Y-Yeah.
Dad.
（創真）親父
（城一郎）ん？
Yeah?
What was...
ここって…
Polar Star Dormitory like back then?
極星寮って親父にとって―
どんなとこだったんだ？
フッ… 面白かったぜ
It was fun.
Everyone worked on perfecting their craft however they could.
みんな好き勝手に
自分の料理を極めてよ
Dad, want to sleep in my room tonight?
（創真）親父
俺の部屋で寝るか？
I guess.
ん？ そうだな…
ハハッ… 創真
お前 303号室かよ
Souma, you're in 303?
Yeah, why?
あっ… そうだけど？
In the middle of the room...
（城一郎）部屋の真ん中辺り…
（創真）ん？
there's a scorch mark from
when a pot fell on the floor.
床に鍋を落とした焦げ跡がある
It used to be my room.
俺が暮らした部屋だ
Fumio-san, let me stay in one of the empty rooms!
（城一郎）ふみ緒さ～ん
どっか空き部屋 貸してくれ
Sure!
（ふみ緒）あいよ！
This was Dad's room.
（創真）この部屋に―
親父が…
Saiba Jouichirou, huh?
（創真）才波城一郎か…
Really now,
俺はその料理人のことを―
just how much do I actually know...
ほとんど何も―
about that man?
知らないのかもしれない
（鳥の鳴き声）
（城一郎）創真　創真！
Souma!
Are you up?
（城一郎）起きたか？
Yeah.
I'm in the kitchen right now.
（城一郎）
今 厨房にいるからよ
Bring your knives and come join me.
お前も自分の包丁持って
下りてきな
Maybe he's prepping breakfast?
（創真）朝食の準備かな？
Come to think of it, why did
Dad come back to Japan?
（創真）そういや 結局 親父は
何で日本に帰ってきたんだろ？
I wonder if it has something to do with a job.
何か仕事でもあったのかね？
Oh, there you are.
おっ 来たな
You've sharpened your knives, right?
包丁は研いであるな？
Of course.
もちろん
I did it last night so the smell of the whetstone—
砥石(といし)のにおいが抜けるように―
Okay, good.
（創真）昨日の晩…
（城一郎）よし オーケーだ
Well, sorry to spring this on you,
（城一郎）
じゃ早速で悪いんだが―
but I need you to show me
how much you've grown...
お前がどれだけ成長したか…
or how much you haven't.
あるいは成長してないのか―
Let's have our first cooking
contest in a long time...
今ここで見せてくれ
久方ぶりに料理勝負と
いこうじゃねえか？
The Demon
Souma.
創真よ
End
Next Episode
Next time on Shokugeki no Souma,
（城一郎）次回「食戟のソーマ」
the sixteenth dish.
16品目
Thanks for waiting!
お待ちどうさま
Menu
The Chef Who's Crossed
a Thousand Leagues
The Chef Who's Crossed a Thousand Leagues.
「万里を駆ける料理人」
Do have a taste.
ご賞味あれ
We have Aldini.
Bow
I have Yukihira.
Mizuhara Megumi:
0-3 on Recruiting Attempts!